<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>About AirlineSim on AirlineSim Handbook</title><link>https://simulogics.github.io/airlinesim-docs/about-airlinesim/</link><description>Recent content in About AirlineSim on AirlineSim Handbook</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://simulogics.github.io/airlinesim-docs/about-airlinesim/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Payment and Credits</title><link>https://simulogics.github.io/airlinesim-docs/about-airlinesim/payment-credits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simulogics.github.io/airlinesim-docs/about-airlinesim/payment-credits/</guid><description>General AirlineSim is a pay-to-play game that works with in-game credits, which you can buy.
When you found a holding on a game world, a certain amount of credits will be deducted every 24h. If your credits balance turns negative, you won’t be able to play AirlineSim anymore, but your airline will still continue to exist, allowing you to recharge your credits still. For a trial account, the grace period is 7 days and for premium accounts it is 28 days before your airlines will be deleted after your credits balance turned negative.</description></item><item><title>Game rules</title><link>https://simulogics.github.io/airlinesim-docs/about-airlinesim/game-rules/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simulogics.github.io/airlinesim-docs/about-airlinesim/game-rules/</guid><description>AirlineSim is an aviation-related, strategic online business simulation, built to entertain and play against other real life players. Each player is doing this in their spare time, to be entertained and to compete with other players in a fair and friendly competition.
General Rules 1 Introduction
1.1 Definitions In Context of the Rules AirlineSim website - All areas of the website ending in airlinesim.aero, this includes forums, game worlds, private messages and in-game message.</description></item><item><title>Game worlds</title><link>https://simulogics.github.io/airlinesim-docs/about-airlinesim/game-worlds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simulogics.github.io/airlinesim-docs/about-airlinesim/game-worlds/</guid><description>Overview You can play on as many game worlds as you like.
Short-term game worlds These are currently Quimby, Otto and Yeager. They usually run for about 8-10 months and then restart again as a new game world.
Short-term game worlds consume 4 credits per day for your first holding and 2 credits per day for every additonal holding.
Long-term game worlds These game worlds are running continuosly with no end date.</description></item><item><title>Exclusive game worlds</title><link>https://simulogics.github.io/airlinesim-docs/about-airlinesim/exclusive-game-worlds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simulogics.github.io/airlinesim-docs/about-airlinesim/exclusive-game-worlds/</guid><description>AirlineSim was created for use with public game worlds, but due to popular demand we&amp;rsquo;re also offering individual game worlds.
However, as the game wasn’t originally intended for this kind of use, an exclusive game world is identical to a public one on the technical level. As a result, the same possibilities for customization as well as the same restrictions apply and settings are being managed by our support staff.</description></item><item><title>Support</title><link>https://simulogics.github.io/airlinesim-docs/about-airlinesim/support/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simulogics.github.io/airlinesim-docs/about-airlinesim/support/</guid><description>There are various channels available to you, in case you need help or have want to send us information.
Forums This is the main place for communication between players of AirlineSim. Go browse the forums and you will find lots of helpful information by other players, answered questions that many other may have asked before!
Discord Our Discord channel is the easiest place for you to find quick help from other users for any game-play questions you may have.</description></item></channel></rss>