<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>About AirlineSim on AirlineSim Handbook</title><link>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/about/</link><description>Recent content in About AirlineSim on AirlineSim Handbook</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Game Concept</title><link>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/about/concept/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/about/concept/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="game-concept">
 Game Concept
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#game-concept">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>AirlineSim is a realistic browser-based business simulation in which you can run your own virtual airline and compete for passengers with other players.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Use a set of comprehensive management tools to set up an aircraft fleet, create cabin configurations and schedule flight plans – all while keeping an eye on the game&amp;rsquo;s real time market and adjusting price and service levels if necessary.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s not all about competition, though: From forming alliances to signing interline agreements and leasing out aircraft – in AirlineSim, you have many ways of interacting with other players and forming connections that last.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Development</title><link>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/about/development/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/about/development/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="development">
 Development
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#development">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="airlinesim">
 AirlineSim
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#airlinesim">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The development of the original game began back in January 2002. Five years later, simulogics was founded and what started out as a hobby soon turned into a full-fledged game project. Over the years, AirlineSim has seen a lot of progress, including game world releases, in-game improvements and last but not least, a steadily growing community.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="airlinesim-technology-demonstrator">
 AirlineSim Technology Demonstrator
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#airlinesim-technology-demonstrator">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In December 2021, the team announced a project called the AirlineSim Technology Demonstrator (ASTD). The ASTD is a prototype that is meant to explore what the game can look like given today&amp;rsquo;s technological possibilities, making it a foundation for the future development of AirlineSim.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Game Worlds</title><link>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/about/game-worlds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/about/game-worlds/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="game-worlds">
 Game Worlds
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#game-worlds">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>After logging into your account, the Dashboard will show a variety of game worlds for you to choose from. The amount of game worlds that you can join isn&amp;rsquo;t limited, so feel free to try out as many as you like. Keep in mind that &lt;a href="https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/about/payment/">credits&lt;/a> will be deducted from your account for every active game world.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="short-term-game-worlds">
 Short-Term Game Worlds
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#short-term-game-worlds">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As the name suggests, short-term game worlds have a limited runtime and usually last for about 8 to 10 months before starting over in a new iteration. You can find out which worlds are currently available in the table below.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Payment System</title><link>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/about/payment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/about/payment/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="payment-system">
 Payment System
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#payment-system">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>AirlineSim utilizes a payment model that is geared towards fairness, transparency and ease-of-use.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This article covers everything you need to know about credits, credit consumption, prices, payment methods and the game&amp;rsquo;s premium features. If you have any questions regarding the payment process, please refer to our &lt;a href="https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/faqs/payments/">Payment FAQ&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="motivation">
 Motivation
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#motivation">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>AirlineSim is a very niche game (= comparatively few active players). It is also intended to be a serious business simulation, and its servers run elaborate simulation models that are very resource-intensive (= high operational costs).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Support</title><link>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/about/support/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/about/support/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="support">
 Support
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#support">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>If you need further help or have any other questions regarding the game, there are various channels of contact available to you.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="forums">
 Forums
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#forums">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As one of the main community platforms, the &lt;a href="https://forums.airlinesim.aero/">forum&lt;/a> provides a wide variety of categories where you can ask questions, discuss the game with fellow players and find lots of helpful information about AirlineSim! Just remember to search for similar topics before starting a new thread, choosing appropriate titles for your posts and, of course, keeping discussions friendly.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>