<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Company Setup on AirlineSim Handbook</title><link>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/advanced/setup/</link><description>Recent content in Company Setup on AirlineSim Handbook</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/advanced/setup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Holdings vs. Subsidiaries</title><link>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/advanced/setup/holdings-vs-subsidiaries/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/advanced/setup/holdings-vs-subsidiaries/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="holdings-vs-subsidiaries">
 Holdings vs. Subsidiaries
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#holdings-vs-subsidiaries">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>When you start out with a new company, you create a holding in the country of your choice and receive a capital of 10 million AS$ (please note that the amount of starting capital can vary depending on the game world). Using that, you can acquire planes and become an operational enterprise. However, you can also use your funds (or parts of them) to create a subsidiary. In that case, your subsidiary can lease or buy planes and operate your airline. So what&amp;rsquo;s the difference?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Traffic Rights</title><link>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/advanced/setup/traffic-rights/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/advanced/setup/traffic-rights/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="traffic-rights">
 Traffic Rights
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#traffic-rights">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>A critical aspect of the game is that airlines are national, not global, entities. Air traffic agreements between individual countries regulate the transport of passengers in the real world and AirlineSim represents this, albeit in a slightly simplified manner.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-are-traffic-rights">
 What are Traffic Rights?
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#what-are-traffic-rights">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>By Traffic Rights we mean the rules that determine whether you can fly passengers between two destinations. Your rights to serve a particular market are determined by the country in which your holding&amp;rsquo;s home base is located. For subsidiaries, the rights are usually based on the location of the holding as well (or the combined amount of shares held if your airline is a listed enterprise).&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>