<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Finances on AirlineSim Handbook</title><link>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/advanced/finances/</link><description>Recent content in Finances on AirlineSim Handbook</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/advanced/finances/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Load Factors</title><link>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/advanced/finances/load-factors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/advanced/finances/load-factors/</guid><description>Load Factors # A plane that flies half empty loses money, so make sure to keep your planes as full as possible. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have enough payload, you need another plane making profit in order to cover for the losses. However, this means that you invested money in two planes and the net result is still zero.
Example
Let&amp;rsquo;s say that you have a plane with 100 seats and the point where you break even is at around 70%.</description></item><item><title>Ticket Prices</title><link>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/advanced/finances/ticket-prices/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/advanced/finances/ticket-prices/</guid><description>Ticket Prices # How much will passengers pay? # Actually, the answer is fairly simple: If you&amp;rsquo;re the only airline in the area, passengers will pay through the nose to board your planes. They may hate you for it, but they will pay. However, you&amp;rsquo;re rarely the only available airline, so here are a few rules of thumb to guide you through the process of choosing ticket prices.
If you&amp;rsquo;re offering decent seats and service, you can try selling tickets that lie 25% above the default price.</description></item><item><title>Leasing and Selling</title><link>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/advanced/finances/leasing-and-selling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/advanced/finances/leasing-and-selling/</guid><description>Leasing and Selling # If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in leasing or selling your owned planes on the aircraft market, you can go to the Fleet Management page and click on the small book icon next to your desired model. This will allow you to put your plane up for sale or lease.
Choosing either will show the associated pricing options, such as the minimum price and the bid interval. Keep in mind that the aircraft&amp;rsquo;s settings, flight plan and seating will be removed once you activate the offer.</description></item><item><title>Initial Public Offerings</title><link>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/advanced/finances/initial-public-offerings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/advanced/finances/initial-public-offerings/</guid><description>Initial Public Offerings # Some game worlds allow players to perform an IPO, which stands for Initial Public Offering. At least two weeks after establishing an enterprise, you may apply for a quotation on the AirlineSim stock market and start trading shares publicly.
Basic Rules # Before we get started, here are some general rules and tips regarding IPOs and stock market transactions that mostly serve to protect new IPOs and avoid illegal actions:</description></item><item><title>Bankruptcy and Loans</title><link>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/advanced/finances/bankruptcy-and-loans/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/advanced/finances/bankruptcy-and-loans/</guid><description>Bankruptcy and Loans # Inability to Pay # Inability to pay or insolvency means that a natural person or legal entity isn&amp;rsquo;t able to pay for bills through their own cash flow, meaning the regular income isn&amp;rsquo;t sufficient to cover the regular costs. In most cases, the credit limit is used up as well. This often results in giving up the company and ceasing commercial operations.
Info
In AirlineSim, there is no overdraft credit to pay leasing installments or salaries from, so your company&amp;rsquo;s liquidity is determined by the balance of your bank account.</description></item></channel></rss>