<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Beginner's Guide on AirlineSim Handbook</title><link>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/beginners-guide/</link><description>Recent content in Beginner's Guide on AirlineSim Handbook</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/beginners-guide/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/beginners-guide/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/beginners-guide/introduction/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="your-first-airline">
 Your First Airline
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#your-first-airline">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;re new to the game and want to know how to get started with your business venture? Well, you have come to the right place!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This tutorial is here to guide you through your first steps in the game, covering everything from setting up your new company and building your fleet to configuring aircraft cabins and activating flight schedules.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ready? Then let&amp;rsquo;s get your airline off the ground!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Company Setup</title><link>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/beginners-guide/company-setup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/beginners-guide/company-setup/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="company-setup">
 Company Setup
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#company-setup">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="planning-the-company-structure">
 Planning the Company Structure
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#planning-the-company-structure">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After creating your AirlineSim account and picking a game world, it can be helpful to think about how you want to structure your company, especially if the world supports &lt;a href="https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/advanced/finances/initial-public-offerings/">Initial Public Offerings (IPOs)&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While you can use the first holding you establish as a regular airline, you won&amp;rsquo;t be able to perform a stock market launch with it. In case you&amp;rsquo;re interested in starting an IPO, you need to create another enterprise as the daughter of your existing holding. The subsidiary can then be traded on the stock market once you go public.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Immediate Delivery Program</title><link>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/beginners-guide/immediate-delivery-program/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/beginners-guide/immediate-delivery-program/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="immediate-delivery-program">
 Immediate Delivery Program
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#immediate-delivery-program">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>During the creation of your company, you may have noticed an in-game message popping up. Whenever you establish a holding in a new game world, you are greeted with a note from the Aircraft Trade and Leasing Organization (ATO) welcoming you to the Immediate Delivery Program (IDP).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This service grants you a starting budget of 10 million AS$ and is meant to get your new company off the ground and ready for the competition.
The advantage of these initial funds is that you can use them to lease new aircraft and get them delivered immediately.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Building Your Fleet</title><link>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/beginners-guide/building-your-fleet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/beginners-guide/building-your-fleet/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="building-your-fleet">
 Building Your Fleet
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#building-your-fleet">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>With your company set up, you probably want to start leasing or buying your first aircraft. Since there is a huge variety of machines to choose from, let&amp;rsquo;s start by evaluating which aircraft type suits your planned operations best!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="choosing-planes">
 Choosing Planes
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#choosing-planes">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="plane.jpg" alt="An Airbus A350 XWB" title="An Airbus A350 XWB"/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, it can be helpful to decide where you want your aircraft to fly to. With some possible routes in mind, you can get a better idea of what your fleet is going to look like.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Creating Routes</title><link>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/beginners-guide/creating-routes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/beginners-guide/creating-routes/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="creating-routes">
 Creating Routes
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#creating-routes">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;ve successfully acquired your first aircraft, so let&amp;rsquo;s start planning your airline&amp;rsquo;s routes! After the previous steps, you might already have a rough idea of where you want to fly, but now we&amp;rsquo;ll have a look at the details.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="finding-airport-information">
 Finding Airport Information
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#finding-airport-information">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="airport_02.png" alt="Airport Details" title="Airport Details"/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in a specific airport, you can search for it by typing its name or IATA code into the bar at the top of the screen. The airport&amp;rsquo;s page offers lots of details, but for now, we&amp;rsquo;ll focus on the Information tab.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hiring Staff</title><link>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/beginners-guide/hiring-staff/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/beginners-guide/hiring-staff/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="hiring-staff">
 Hiring Staff
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#hiring-staff">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>With the routes set up, let&amp;rsquo;s move on to your staff!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="employing-pilots">
 Employing Pilots
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#employing-pilots">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>An aircraft needs pilots to fly, so we have to hire or train them first. Some crew members will already be added by default, but let&amp;rsquo;s find out how to employ pilots manually.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, select the Management tab and go to Crew Management. On the left, you&amp;rsquo;ll see a list of the employed and required pilots, grouped together by aircraft category. As pilots can&amp;rsquo;t work the whole day, the number of required pilots is higher than actually necessary for a flight. For example, if your plane flies 20 hours per day, you need three crews to operate it and a fourth crew to replace pilots on sick leave or holiday.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Service Profiles</title><link>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/beginners-guide/service-profiles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/beginners-guide/service-profiles/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="defining-service-profiles">
 Defining Service Profiles
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#defining-service-profiles">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="crackers-or-caviar">
 Crackers or Caviar?
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#crackers-or-caviar">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Remember the days when airlines offered free drinks and a newspaper on every flight? It didn&amp;rsquo;t cost them much, but passengers appreciated the service.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our virtual passengers like to be pampered, too! Fortunately, good on-board service - drinks, meals, newspapers and so on - isn&amp;rsquo;t that expensive and the higher rating is definitely worth the price.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Business and first class passengers are harder to please, but if you offer first class seats, then why not offer first class service? It&amp;rsquo;s not profitable to install big seats and sell cheap tickets because the passengers dislike your service.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Configuring the Cabins</title><link>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/beginners-guide/cabin-configuration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/beginners-guide/cabin-configuration/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="configuring-the-cabins">
 Configuring the Cabins
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#configuring-the-cabins">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Before you can hit the skies, you need to equip your aircraft with a cabin and configure its seat layout - regardless of whether you own new or used machines. Let&amp;rsquo;s see how it&amp;rsquo;s done!&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote class="book-hint info">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Info&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
This step does not apply if you want to operate cargo aircraft. Though it&amp;rsquo;s not the best, there is a default configuration already installed in all of your new aircraft.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Assigning Cabin and Crew</title><link>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/beginners-guide/assigning-cabin-and-crew/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/beginners-guide/assigning-cabin-and-crew/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="assigning-cabin-and-crew">
 Assigning Cabin and Crew
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#assigning-cabin-and-crew">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Now that you&amp;rsquo;ve set up cabins and hired staff, it&amp;rsquo;s time to assign them to your aircraft.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the Operations tab, click on Fleet Management and pick the fleet that your aircraft is assigned to. Right now, this will probably be the default fleet which all of your purchased and leased aircraft are added to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="fleet_03.png" alt="Assigning Seating and Crew" title="Assigning Seating and Crew"/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next, select the aircraft in question. This opens an Actions window in which you can specify cabin and crew. You can simultaneously assign one cabin configuration to several aircraft of the same model variant. Again, this does not apply to cargo machines.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Maintenance</title><link>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/beginners-guide/maintenance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/beginners-guide/maintenance/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="maintenance">
 Maintenance
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#maintenance">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="booking-maintenance">
 Booking Maintenance
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#booking-maintenance">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Okay, you have your aircraft, routes, service, staff and cabins all figured out - time to start flying? Not just yet, you still need a maintenance provider! Without repairs, your aircraft won&amp;rsquo;t be flying for very long…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="maintenance_03.png" alt="Choosing a Contractor" title="Choosing a Contractor"/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the Operations tab, select Maintenance and choose a maintenance company servicing your aircraft. There are several options with certain advantages and disadvantages. Every provider has different values regarding price, quality and the duration of maintenance.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Scheduling Flights</title><link>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/beginners-guide/scheduling-flights/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/beginners-guide/scheduling-flights/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="scheduling-flights">
 Scheduling Flights
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#scheduling-flights">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>With the maintenance provider ready to go, it&amp;rsquo;s finally time to get your aircraft flying! This can be quite simple or a bit complicated, depending on where you are, what your airline is trying to achieve and how much competition you&amp;rsquo;re facing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This tutorial will focus on getting a basic flight plan up and running, but a lot of the more advanced concepts should be pretty self-evident by the time you&amp;rsquo;re through with it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Congratulations!</title><link>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/beginners-guide/congratulations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/beginners-guide/congratulations/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="congratulations">
 Congratulations!
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#congratulations">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The title says it all - you have successfully completed our beginner&amp;rsquo;s guide! With your new airline, you&amp;rsquo;re well equipped to tackle the daily challenges of the aviation business. Feel free to experiment with different ideas and, if you&amp;rsquo;re looking for further help, consult the advanced section of the handbook as well as our &lt;a href="https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/about/support/">support article&lt;/a>. With that said - happy playing!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>