<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>User Interface on AirlineSim Handbook</title><link>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/user-interface/</link><description>Recent content in User Interface on AirlineSim Handbook</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/user-interface/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Company Overview</title><link>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/user-interface/company-overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/user-interface/company-overview/</guid><description>Company Overview # Hovering over your company&amp;rsquo;s name at the top left of the screen provides you with several options regarding your enterprise.
Overview # The dashboard is separated into seven parts (also called widgets) - Company, Upcoming Events, Notepad, Stock, Financial Rating, Image and Subsidiaries - and is handy to look up quick information about your company.
Company # The Company widget displays the logo (if you uploaded one) as well as the most important information about the enterprise, such as its name, code, hub, home country, airline rating, fleet size and number of employees.</description></item><item><title>Commercial Tab</title><link>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/user-interface/commercial-tab/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/user-interface/commercial-tab/</guid><description>Commercial Tab # This part of the menu consists of a Network Planning, Sales &amp;amp; Distribution, Product &amp;amp; Customer Service and a Business Development section.
Network Planning # Scheduling # Here, you can manage flight schedules for a specific route. After selecting an airport pair on the left, you get information on related flight numbers and product ratings.
In the text field below the page title, you can quickly switch to another airport pair.</description></item><item><title>Operations Tab</title><link>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/user-interface/operations-tab/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/user-interface/operations-tab/</guid><description>Operations Tab # The Operations tab is divided into Flight and Ground Operations.
Flight Operations # Fleet Management # The Fleet Management page shows your acquired aircraft and lets you organize them by assigning them to fleets.
A new fleet can be created by using the button on the top right. On the left, you get a list of your existing fleets as well as the option to delete them.</description></item><item><title>Management Tab</title><link>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/user-interface/management-tab/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/user-interface/management-tab/</guid><description>Management Tab # The Management tab grants access to the Procurement, Human Resources, Investments and Finance menus.
Procurement # Aircraft Manufacturers # On this page, you can see all the available aircraft types grouped by manufacturer and category (props, regional jets, narrow- and wide-bodies). Clicking on an aircraft model gives you a summary of its related variants and some general information like their capacities, speed and range.</description></item><item><title>Database Tab</title><link>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/user-interface/database-tab/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/user-interface/database-tab/</guid><description>Database Tab # The database tab lets you access important game resources like different directories, the Online Reservation System (ORS) and the game rules.
Directories # Countries # This section provides a list of all available countries in the game. Selecting a country will lead you to its information page where you can find details regarding its signed treaties, the market access for foreign investors as well as its airports.</description></item><item><title>Support Tab</title><link>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/user-interface/support-tab/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/user-interface/support-tab/</guid><description>Support Tab # If you&amp;rsquo;re experiencing issues with the game or have ideas for improvements, this page helps you find the correct support channel. Our support article lists all the relevant details.</description></item><item><title>Community Tab</title><link>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/user-interface/community-tab/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/user-interface/community-tab/</guid><description>Community Tab # You want to connect with other players or find out about the latest game updates? The Community tab offers all the links you need.
Whether it&amp;rsquo;s the AirlineSim blog, the forums, our Discord server or the game&amp;rsquo;s Twitter and Facebook page - there&amp;rsquo;s lots of ways to stay in the loop and become part of our community!
The Community tab also offers a link to our second title Prosperous Universe, a browser-based space economy game!</description></item><item><title>Private Messages</title><link>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/user-interface/private-messages/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/user-interface/private-messages/</guid><description>Private Messages # This tab grants you access to the in-game messages you have sent and received.
Messages are sorted into different mail boxes that each consist of an inbox and an outbox. Here you can reply, mark them as read or unread and delete them.
If you want to send an in-game message, look up the respective airline or user profile and click on the Send Message / Send a Message to This User button on the top right.</description></item><item><title>Settings</title><link>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/user-interface/settings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://handbook.airlinesim.aero/en/docs/user-interface/settings/</guid><description>Settings # Account Settings # Your Profile # The Your Profile section provides data such as the account&amp;rsquo;s username, status and email address. On the right, you&amp;rsquo;ll find a list of your holdings and subsidiaries in the game world.
Your Holdings # This page shows your daily credit consumption as well as your current balance. You&amp;rsquo;ll also see a list of your active holdings on the right.</description></item></channel></rss>